PROPOSITION.
TRISH: NANCY PELOSI TELLING THE
MEDIA THE REPUBLICANS CAM PLANT
ABOUT THE SO-CALLED
WHISTLEBLOWER NOT HAVING
FIRST-HAND KNOWLEDGE OF THE
COMPLAINT IS WITHOUT MERIT AND
FRAUDULENT.
BECAUSE MAYBE I'M GOING OUT ON A
LIMB HERE.
BUT IF YOU ARE UPSET ABOUT HOW
SOMETHING IS BEING HANDLED, IT'S
USUALLY BECAUSE YOU HAVE
FIRST-HAND KNOWLEDGE ABOUT HOW
IT'S BEING HAND.
TO A BUNCH OF OFFICE GOES UP AND
REPORT THAT AS A SO-CALLED
WHISTLEBLOWER, THAT'S KIND OF
SNOWFLAKE.
BUT THAT'S WHAT THIS
WHISTLEBLOWER DID,  *, THINK
ABOUT THAT TERM.
INTERESTING, RIGHT?
THAT DOESN'T SIT WELL WITH ONE
REAL WHISTLEBLOWER.
A GENTLEMAN WHO RISKED HIS
ENTIRE CAREER CALLING OUT THE
CIA FOR ITS TORTURE PROBLEMS
WOUND UP IN JAIL FOR IT.
JOHN KIRIAKOU BLEW THE LID ON
THE CIA TORTURE PROGRAM.
AND HE WAS PROSECUTED BY THE
OBAMA ADMINISTRATION.
HE SAYS HE AND EDWARD SNOWDEN
HAVE RISKED EVERYTHING TO INFORM
THE AMERICAN PEOPLE.
THIS WHISTLEBLOWER DOESN'T KNOW
THE MEANING OF THE WORD.
I AM HAPPY TO HAVE JOHN KIRIAKOU
ON TO EXPLAIN.
WALK US THROUGH IT.
YOU RISKED A LOT.
YOU WOUND UP ALMOST THREE YEARS
IN JAIL BECAUSE OF YOUR EXPOSURE
OF A PROGRAM THAT MADE A LOT OF
NEWS AND A LOT OF AMERICANS WERE
SHOCKED BY.
BUT THIS WHISTLEBLOWER, DOES HE
DESERVE THE SAME TERM?
>> I'M NOT CALLING HIM A
WHISTLEBLOWER.
I DON'T THINK HE'S A
THERE IS A LEGAL DEFINITION OF
WHISTLE BLOWING IN THE UNITED
STATES IT'S WRITTEN INTO THE
WHISTLEBLOWER PROTECTION LAW.
ANY PERSON WHO BRINGS TO LIGHT
EVIDENCE OF WASTE, FRAUD, ABUSE,
ILLEGALITY OR THREAT TO THE PUN-
TO THE PUBLIC HEALTH OR PUBLIC
SAFETY.
THERE IS A WAY TO GO ABOUT DOING
IT.
THE WHISTLEBLOWER MAY HAVE BEGUN
THE PROCESS THE WAY HE WAS
SUPPOSED TO BEGIN THE.
THEN IT SPIRALED OUT OF CONTROL.
I WOULDN'T CALL HIM A
WHISTLEBLOWER SO MUCH AS I HAVE
CALLED HIM AN ANONYMOUS SOURCE
FOR THE DEMOCRATIC STAFF MEMBERS
OF THE HOUSE INTELLIGENCE
COMMITTEE.
TRISH: HE DID MEET WITH ADAM
SCHIFF'S STAFF BEFORE FILING
THIS COMPLAINT.
IT TAINTS THIS IN SOME WAYS.
>> IT DOES.
THAT'S A VIOLATION OF THE LETTER
OF THE LAW.
WHAT YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO DO
ACCORDING TO THE WHISTLEBLOWER
PROTECTION LAW.
YOU ARE SUPPOSED TO GO TO THE
INSPECTOR GENERAL, THEN THE
INSPECTOR GENERAL INVESTIGATES
AND THE INSPECTOR GENERAL GOES
TO THE COMMITTEE.
YOU DON'T GO TO THE COMMITTEE
FIRST.
WHAT HAPPENED IN THIS CASE, THE
WHISTLEBLOWER FIRST WENT TO
COMMITTEE, THEN TO THE INSPECTOR
GENERAL, THEN THE I.G. WENT TO
THE LEGAL STAFF, THE GENERAL
CROWN GENERAL COUNSEL AND THEN
WENT TO THE DNI IG IT WAS AN
UNWIELDY SITUATION AND IT SPUN
OUT OF CONTROL.
TRISH: DO YOU THINK THIS IS
EFFECTIVELY THE DEEP STATE AT
WORK, THERE ARE A LOT OF PEOPLE
WHO DIDN'T LIKE THIS PRESIDENT?
>> ABSOLUTELY YES.
YOU KNOW, PEOPLE LAUGH AT US
SOMETIMES WHEN WE USE THE TERM
DEEP STATE.
BUT THERE IS A DEEP STATE.
THE DEEP STATE IS REAL.
YOU DON'T HAVE TO CALL IT THE
DEEP 8.
YOU CAN CALL IT THE FEDERAL
BUREAUCRACY.
YOU CAN CALL IT THE GOVERNMENT.
BUT IT'S A DEEP STATE.
THIS DEEP STATE FROM THE
BEGINNING OF THIS PRESIDENT'S
ADMINISTRATION HAS SHOW THE HIM
ILL.
TRISH: TALK TO ME ABOUT THE TERM
AGAIN WHISTLEBLOWER.
HOW WOULD YOU CHARACTERIZE THIS
PERSON?
WOULD YOU SAY DEMOCRATIC
OPERATIVE?
WOULD YOU SAY LEAKER?
HOW WOULD YOU DEFINE?
CONSIDER WHAT THE MEDIA HAS
DONE, RIGHT?
THEY PUT THE PERSON WAY, WAY UP
ON A PEDESTAL AND THEY ARE JUST
A CRUSADER FOR JUSTICE.
AND YOU ON THE OTHER HARDEN AND
SOME OTHERS THAT RISKED A LOT
HAVE DONE MUCH MORE IN TERMS OF
EXPOSING THINGS THAT PROBABLY
NEED TO GET EXPOSED.
THIS GUY IS REPORTING GOSSIP.
>> I WOULD CALL THIS GUY A BUSY
BODY.
I WOULDN'T CALL HIM A
WHISTLEBLOWER.
I AM NOT EVEN SHIRE WOULD CALL
HIM A DEMOCRATIC OPEN RAW TOUGH
AS MUCH AS A DEMOCRATIC
OPERATIVE WANNABE.
YOU WONDER YES DIDN'T THINK THIS
THROUGH.
IF HE WERE GOING TO TRY TO DO AN
END RUN AROUND THE PROCESS AND
GO DIRECTLY TO THE COMMITTEE,
CERTAINLY WE WOULD FIGURE OUT
WHO WAS, WE WOULD SEE THOSE
PICTURES OF HIM WITH JOE BIDEN
AND WITH HILLARY CLINTON, AND
WITH ALL THESE SOME OTHER
DEMOCRATIC PARTY LEADERS.
DID HE THINK HE COULD KEEP THAT
QUIET OR SECRET?
THAT'S IMPORTANT.
>> THAT'S IMPORTANT TO KNOW.
BECAUSE IT COLORS HIS LACK OF
OBJECT TEST.
D
OBJECTIVITY.
>> HE DID NOT HAVE FIRSTHAND
KNOWLEDGE OF THIS PHONE CALL.
NOW BASED ON WHAT WE HAVE HEARD
SO FAR ON CAPITOL HILL.
HE DIDN'T EVEN HAVE SECOND HAND
KNOWLEDGE OF THE SITUATION.
TRISH ARE'S APPARENTLY CASHING
IN.
HE GOT A GoFundMe ACCOUNT THAT
RAISED $225,000.
WE DON'T KNOW WHERE THAT MONEY
CAME FROM.
YOU ARE NOT SUPPOSED TO
CONTRIBUTE AS A FOREIGNER.
BUT WHO IS TO SAY.
WHAT IS YOUR THOUGHT ON THAT?
>> THAT'S A VERY, VERY GOOD
POINT AND IMPORTANT POINT.
WE ARE NOT SUPPOSED TO SAY THIS
MAN'S NAME BECAUSE HE'S SUPPOSE
TO BE PROTECTED AND THIS IS
SUPPOSED TO BE A SECRET PROCESS.
NOW HE WILL GET RICH WITH A
GoFundMe CAMPAIGN.
IT DOESN'T MAKE ANY SENSE TO ME,
CERTAINLY NOT ANY LEGAL SENSE AT